Guide to the John Poulos and Constantine Poulos Papers TAM.114
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
John and Constantine Poulos Papers
1921-1978
1940-1950
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Poulos, Constantine, 1916-1986
Poulos, John, 1911-1980
TAM.114
12.5 Linear Feet 20 boxes and six folders in a shared manuscript box
John Poulos (1911-1980) was a Marxist, Trotskyist, writer and labor organizer from Lynn, Massachusetts. He organized Food Workers Local 701 of the AFL, and was a delegate to the CIO founding convention in 1938. He served on the national committee of the Socialist Workers Party, and later the Workers Party, and wrote extensively for its newspaper, Labor Action. He was involved in the fight against the Greek military dictatorship and set up a collection on Greek radicalism at the Tamiment Library. His brother Constantine ("Connie") Poulos (1916-1986) was a liberal journalist and founder and editor of political monthly: The Hellenic Spectator. Constantine was a journalist for the Overseas News Agency during World War II, and reported on the Greek resistance. After WWII, Constantine Poulos served as a liaison and translator for negotiations between American officials and the Greek resistance, namely, EAM-ELAS. He was expelled from Greece under the charge that he was "pro-communist". Constantine Poulos returned to the U.S. where he wrote for The Nation, was an editor of Holiday, and bought a weekly newspaper in Jamestown, NY, where he was to win a Pulitzer Prize for community journalism. The collection includes correspondence and articles by the Poulos brothers, as well as pamphlets and assorted materials pertaining to their individual political pursuits.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
John Poulos (1911-1980), student and documenter of Greek and Greek-American radicalism, and a son of Greek immigrants, was born in 1911 in Lynn, Massachusetts. While in his twenties, and a food worker, he organized Food Workers Local 701 of the AFL and led the fledgling union into the emerging CIO, and was a delegate to the CIO founding convention in 1938. A Marxist, Poulos belonged to, and served on the national committee of the Socialist Workers Party, a Trotskyist organization. Later, in the 1940s he joined the Workers Party, also a Trotskyist organization. He served on its central committee, and wrote extensively for its newspaper, Labor Action. He was also active in the United Auto Workers, but by the late 1950s was blacklisted for his radical views. Remaining polticially active, he was involved in the fight against the Greek military dictatorship (1967-74). In the 1970s Poulos became an activist scholar of Greek studies, setting up a collection on Greek radicalism at the Tamiment Library. He died on December 20, 1980.
Constantine ("Connie") Poulos (1916-1986), John's younger brother, was born in 1916. Although familiar with Marxism through his older brother, Constantine was a liberal. In 1940 he was founder and editor of The Hellenic Spectator, a monthly of politics and the arts. With the outbreak of World War II, Constantine took a job as a journalist for the Overseas News Agency. He was eventually assigned to report on the Greek resistance and in 1943 became the first correspondent to enter occupied Greece, where he made his way to the mountains and came into contact with the communist-led united from resistance, the National Liberation Front (EAM-ELAS). Poulos's reports were picked up by hundreds of American newspapers, including the Greek press, and he also wrote interpretive essays which appeared in The Nation. After WWII, Poulos also reported from Bulgaria, Poland, Romania, Hungary and Palestine. At the war's end, Constatine Poulos served as a liaison and translator between American officials and resistance notables. He urged that EAM-ELAS be given at least an equal voice in the government being shaped for postwar Greece. While freely ackowledging the communist leadership of EAM-ELAS, Poulos felt that the resistance fighters were Greece's best democrats and that they would function honorably in a regime which guaranteed their political rights. This view ran counter to what became American policy, and Poulos was expelled from Greece under vague charges that he was "pro-communist". Poulos returned to the U.S. and eventually bought a weekly newspaper in Jamestown, NY, where he was to win a Pulitzer Prize for community journalism. He was able to get an editorial position at Holiday magazine (1965-70), and wrote about the Greek Junta for The Nation. Constantine Poulos died June 3, 1986.
Scope and Content Note
The materials in the collection were created and accumulated by John and Constantine Poulos. The collection contains correspondence, dispatches and articles, typescripts, political cartoons, internal documents and bulletins of left-wing organizations, government documents, pamphlets and other published materials. The bulk and richest portion of the collection documents the Greek Civil War, 1944-49, and the history of Greek Trotskyism. There is also good documentation of the period of the Greek Junta, 1967-74, and resistance thereto, and of Greek-American radicalism. The collection is organized into five series, described below. In addition, three linear feet of Greek language publications have been separated for future integration into the Library's book, serial and ephemera holdings.
Series I, Constantine Poulos' writings and correspondence, offers keen insight into the situation in Greece, 1944-49, and the reaction of Britain and the U.S. In addition to his press dispatches and published articles, there are political cartoons by Poulos, U.S. government documents, and pamphlets published in the U.S. and Britain in support of the guerilla forces. This series also documents the consequences for Poulos' journalism career of his reportage on Greece.
Series II documents the Greek Resistance and Civil War and its Aftermath. Materials include EAM-ELAS communiques and central committee documents, underground leaflets and newspapers, reports on prisoners, and Connie Poulos memoranda to the U.S. government. There are also documents of several Trotskyist organizations, Greek trade unions, and British and American intelligence reports and diplomatic papers. Also included are pamphlets on the resistance groups that were published for American mass audiences. In addition there are materials from the late 1940s to the late 1970s connected to the development of the Greek radical movement and American reaction to that development.
Series III is one of the most extensive collections on Greek Trotskyism. Much of it was collected by John Poulos in the 1970s for a projected definitive history of Greek Trotskyism. Included are materials on the Greek Archeio-Marxists, a non-Stalinist group (never part of the Third International) which originated in the late 1910s and ultimately merged with the Trotskyist groups in the late 1930s.
Series IV contains the correspondence Poulos undertook to locate the materials on Greek Trotskyism and the rest of the collection. Much of this correspondence clarifies the identity, contributions, and fates of various Greek Trotskyists in the U.S. and Greece. Among his American correspondents were Trotskyists Hugo Oehler and Albert Glotzer.
Series V contains materials on the anti-junta movement of 1967-1974. Most of this material was published in the U.S. by collectives of radicals and liberals and provides a sense of the activity within the U.S. and of the major issues at stake. Other materials deal with the struggles in Greece itself.
Series VI contains books and serials in Greek, awaiting processing and cataloging.
Series VII contains a scrapbook of clippings on the Greek Civil War from 1940-1948.
Arrangement
Organized into eight series: I. Constance Poulos writings and correspondence; II. Greek Wartime Resistance (WWII), Civil War, and the Aftermath; III. Greek Trotskyism and early Marxism; IV. John Poulos correspondence and Fourth International; V. Junta and Resistance; VI. Greek language books, serials, and miscellaneous published materials, unprocessed; VII. Scrapbook on Greek Civil War; VIII, Addendum.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
The Newsmen's Commission to Investigate the Murder of George Polk (Tamiment 159)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by John Poulos, circa 1970. The accession number associated with this gift is 1970.002. Photographs separated during initial processing were also reincorporated into the collection. The accession number associated with this material is 1970.001. Additionally, several photographs found in the repository were added to the collection in 2014. The accession number associated with these items is 2014.073.
Food industry and trade -- Employees.; Greek Americans.; Radicals -- United States.; Communists -- United States.; Political cartoons.; Dispatches.; Socialists -- United States.; Greece -- History -- Civil War, 1944-1949; Journalists -- United States.; Communism -- Greece.; Greece -- History -- 1967-1974.; Labor unions -- Greece; Correspondence.; Pamphlets.; Glotzer, Albert, 1908-1999.; Workers Party (1940-1949); Ethnikon Apeleutherōtikon Metōpon (Greece); International Union, United Automobile Workers of America (CIO); Poulos, John, 1911-1980; Oehler, Hugo; Hellenic Spectator; Socialist Workers Party; AFL-CIO; Poulos, Constantine, 1916-1986; Poulos, John, 1911-1980
- Series I: Constance Poulos -- Writings and Correspondence
  - Subseries I:A: Connie - Correspondence: Greece
    - J. Poulos letters to L.S. on "smears", undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Subseries I:B: Connie - Balkans
    - Threat on Hitler's moral order, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Dispatches - Bulgaria, 1942-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dispatches - Poland, 1940-1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dispatches - Romania, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Dispatches - Hungary, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Subseries I:C: Press Notes
    - Articles written by or referred to Connie Poulos, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Connie: Ouster from Palestine, editorials., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Connie: Editorials and articles using his material and his name, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      General note
      (originals discarded 12/87)
    - Connie: Articles quoting him, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      (incomplete; originals discarded 12/87)
    - Connie: Editorials and articles in reference to him, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Connie: Articles quoting him, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Connie: Editorials and articles quoting him, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Subseries I:D: Connie - Jerusalem
    - Dispatches, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Dispatches - Rhodes and Greece, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Dispatches - Israel, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - (a) No by-lines - Israel, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Paper on Israel post-1948, ca.1948 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Telegrams and articles, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Stories, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Palestine, Oct 1945 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      For more articles on the ousting of C. Poulos from Palestine see section III, folder 2.
    - Palestine, Nov 1945 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Palestine, Dec 1945 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Palestine, Feb 1946 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Subseries I:E: Greece: Articles and Correspondence
    - Polk murder, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Extracts from the Greek Press, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Nat Herald Puzzle Series, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
      (author unknown)
    - Articles -, Mar 1944 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      (incomplete article enclosed)
    - Ariicles -, Apr 1944 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Poulos, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Connie - National Herald, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Connie - Greece, Jul 1944-Aug 1944, Oct 1944-Nov 1944 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      (Greek)
    - Connie - Ass. clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - British agent - David Balfour a.k.a. Father Demetrios, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Middle-East mutiny, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Nation: Listing of articles sent to Stavrianos, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Connie: Ahepan Magazine, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - The Book, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Dispatches, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Connie: Visas, etc., undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Connie: The Nation, 1944-1947 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Connie: The Nation, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Connie: The Nation, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Connie: The Nation, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Connie: The New Repubulic, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Expelled from Austria, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Connie: Barred from Germany, Jul 17, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - C. Poulos' cabled articles, Dec 1944-Mar 1945 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      (Carbons; some of these articles must have been censored completely for they do not appear in the ONA printed papers)
    - Connie: Original or typed correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Connie: Greece, Feb 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      (Greek and English)
    - Connie: Greece, 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Connie: Greece, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - ONA Mail, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Connie's Book, undated (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
    - Cyprus, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - C. Poulos' room broken into, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - To Poulos from F. Kirchwey, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Mowrer, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Rome Stars and Stripes, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Dispatches - Austria, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Poulos pages 22-77, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - C. Poulos NANA, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Connie, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      (place of print unknown)
    - Connie - Original magazine articles, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - To John from Connie, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Biological sketches, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Subseries I:F: General
    - Hands-ears-feet, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Movies, radio, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Facial expressions, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Latin Areriea, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Cartoons: Labor, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Cartoon Ideas, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Cartoons, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 200, Folder 22)
    - Cartoons: Animals, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 200, Folder 23)
      (see also cartoons: farmers)
    - Cartoons: Workers, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 200, Folder 24)
    - Cartoons: American life and scenes[ ]-Punch, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 200, Folder 25)
    - Cartoons: Political figures, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 200, Folder 26)
    - Cartoons: Farmers, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 200, Folder 27)
  - Subseries I:G: Connie: Literary works
    - Unpublished fiction, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Originals, 1944-1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Subseries I:H: Biography and blacklist
    - Unfiled-Connie-2, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Connie's biography, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Blacklisted, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Maragon, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Connie hounded - Section I, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Connie hounded - Section II, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Connie: Personal narrative, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - [Connie's book], undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Cartoons, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
      (located in Box 10 - subject box)
  - Subseries I:I: Jamestown Sun
    - Jamestown Sun, undated (Box 3, Folder data_value_missing_af91fe9ff0f82812c073d265871bbf54)
  - Subseries I:J: Connie's early writings
    - Connie: Spectator, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Hellenic Spectator, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Connie: Broun, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Subseries I:K: Photos
    - Greece: Starvation, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Subseries I:L: Manuscripts
    - Petsopoulos, John - "England at the war...", undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Lars Barentzen, Copenhagen - Demostration on, Dec 1944 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Subseries I:M: U.S.A Official
    - U. S. Army, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - O.W.I. Reports, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Greece Atrocities - EAM of civilians, 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Hostages, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Go Where, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - White Book, Feb 1945-Jun 1945 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Subseries I:N: U.S.A. Journals and Newspapers
    - Bloody Sunday 12/3/44, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Censorship, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Articles by others on Greece, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Greece: A.C. Sedgwick, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
      (NY Times)
    - U.S. Journal articles on Greece, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Yank, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Washington Post, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - United Press, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Time, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Edmund Wilson - New Yorker, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - New York Times, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - New York Post, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Life, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - New York Herald Tribune, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Colliers, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Christian Science Monitor, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Boston Globe, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Additional Writings of Constantine Poulos, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Scope and Content Note
      "GI Carmen," "On a Darkling Plain: A Sketch," "Summing Up," "Then They Took Us Seriously," and two untitled works.
    - Pamphlets: Murder Inc. in Greece Greece of Tomorrow Greece Fights Justice for Greece Challenge to Freedom Near east problems Greece(Book Digest) Greek Northern Epirus Tyranny and Terror Appeal of British Troops from Greece Greek Liberation The truth about Greece American aid to Greece Greece fights for freedom "Democracy is taking a beating in Greece" A Summary of Greek Internal Politics The youth of Greece, undated (Box 4, Folder data_value_missing_cc94cec57f41be7f496fcea17ee048be)
- Series II: Greek Wartime (WWII) Resistance & Aftermath
  - Subseries II:A: Newspapers
    - Greece: Right wing Papers -, Dec 1944 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Athens: Extracts from Athenian Press, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Greece: Hellenic News Service, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Yugoslavia, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Greece: British Press on Greece, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Underground Press: Occupied Greece, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Subseries II:B: Bibliographies-Indexes-References
    - Books, articles re: Greece, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Subseries II:C: Letters, memorandums
    - Greece: post-, Dec 1944 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - To political and T.U. leaders in U.S. and Britain, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Subseries II:D: Prisoner Reports
    - Greece: Prisoner letters, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Subseries II:E: Appeals to U.S.,Britain,U.S.S.R.
    - Greece: Appeals to heads of government; Trade Unions, etc. -, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Poems of the underground, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Subseries II:F: Articles
    - Connie: Dispatches from Greece, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Greece: L.S. Stavrianos Studies, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Subseries II:G: Mutiny in the mid-east - 1944
    - Summary Account, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
      (in Greek)
    - Report, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Memorandums to the U.S. government, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper articles, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Telegrams, etc. - Mutineers lay down arms, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Subseries II:H: Lebanon Conference - May 1944
    - Lebanon Conference -, May 1944 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Lebanon: To Papandreou by [Souolos] Stratis, Rouson, Jul 9, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Lebanon Rousos, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Greece: Lebanon, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Subseries II:I: EAM Communications
    - Central Committee(Announcements), memorandums, etc. -, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Leaflets, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Subseries II:J: Leaflets, papers, letters, cartoons
    - Greece: German soldiers, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Subseries II:K: ELAS - Greece
    - ELAS - Greece, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Army Orders, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - EPON: Leaflets, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
      (Youth Underground)
    - ELAS Leaders bring back to Greece old party leaders, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Popoff Letters, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Subseries II:L: Greece - EPON
    - ETTON, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Subseries II:M: PEEA
    - PEEA and T.U. releases, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Subseries II:N: KKE
    - KKE Leaflets, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Subseries II:O: British Documents
    - MacVeagh Papers, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Lt. Gen. R.M. Scobie Communiques/Correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - British Intelligence, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Churchill's Verbatim to Press Correspondents, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - British Parliments - Debates, summaries, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Review of Athens Press, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Plaka Agreement, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Byford Jones, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Caserta Agreement, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - NY Times - A.C. Sedgewick, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Newspaper Clippings in English and Greek, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Poetry, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - White Book, May 1944-Mar 1945 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      (English)
    - White Book, May 1944-Mar 1945 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Greece T.U., undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Subseries II:P: Greece Trade Union
    - Lebanon, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Mutiny in the Mid-east, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Censorship, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - 4th International Magazine - Civil War in Greece, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Civil War in Greece, 1943-1949 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Underground Leaflets, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Greece: U.S. Army, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - OWI Reports, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - EAM Communications, etc., undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - ELAS Communications, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Subseries II:Q: EAM
    - Pamphlets: Britain in Greece The Third War How and the people's liberation struggle of Greece met with defeat The campaign in Greece and Crete The fight in Greece Greece: the facts The truth about Greece Greece is our concern Tragedy in Greece Inside Free Greece The Case For Greece, undated (Box 6, Folder data_value_missing_80769dea7d681d1b28770d04005dff75)
    - A bag full of steel character plates, undated (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_c25576c0a801ac4f519b27b311f8090f)
    - Pamphlets and one hard-cover book, undated (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_0c716e73f45a54d13900519946867fc0)
    - The position in Greece, undated (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_3ff9846c3b025707f233bb4983ad69f6)
    - Evidence in support of the Greek Appeal to the security council, undated (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_e48f3b8baa10d00da1d3d7df388b0382)
    - Newsletter of the Cyprus Solidarity Committee, undated (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_0774d6cd937513765749036809cb1e01)
    - Greece, undated (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_e7094b6323d9acd8f2bc0b193aaf5d7a)
    - Journal of the Hellenic American Society - Winter, 1974 (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_d11b90cdbfeff0030814c460599642b2)
    - Journal of the Hellenic American Society -, 1974 (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_b64cc059a87db82ade06ccd7844a5387)
    - The Coffeehouse, undated (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_ec2f44260f70d3f41a87d617399903d3)
    - Fascism in Greece and why it happened, undated (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_774d0762ee7084abe526b5f8e6829183)
    - (Pamphlet in Greek), undated (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_f2cbc662d4ba38b2f91a804f38aada30)